## **Priyanka Singh**

Rochester, NH 03867

Phone: 603-978-8279 | Email: <a href="mailto:priyankasingh30@gmail.com">priyankasingh30@gmail.com</a> | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-singh-94014719/ | GitHub: https://github.com/singhpri30 |

Portfolio: <a href="https://singhpri30.github.io/New-Portfolio/">https://singhpri30.github.io/New-Portfolio/</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with experience in design, analysis, development, and testing of user interface framework in various web-based applications. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills. Strong analytical and troubleshooting skills combined with quality work within the period. An excellent team player, experience working in the agile team model.

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from University of New Hampshire (2020 Batch) BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (B.Tech.) IN Electronics and Communication, 2007, M.M.M.E.C Gorakhpur, India.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, AJAX, JSON, React.js

Backend: Node.js, MYSQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Oracle 10g, Sequelize, Mongoose

DevOps: GitHub, Heroku

Ticket Management Tools: JIRA, ALM, TFS, Mantis.

Automation Tool: QF-Test.

Methodologies: Waterfall and Agile.

#### **PROJECTS**

**Booktivist | Back-End Developer|** 

**GitHub Repo Link:** <u>https://github.com/Team-1-UNH-Bootcamp/Booktivist</u> **Deployed App:** <u>https://ancient-escarpment-64438.herokuapp.com/</u>

- Description: Kid Booktivist is an application that assists parents in their search to find books for their children that deal with issues of equality, diversity, equity and social justice.
- **Responsibilities:** Designed Database models using Sequelize ORM, implemented user authentication, and authorization functionality using passport.js. Worked on APIs CRUD actions for MyLibrary page.
- Tools / Languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, API, Ajax, Sequelize ORM, MYSQL, Passport.js, Exprees.js, Node.js, Postman.

## **Priyanka Singh**

Rochester, NH 03867

Phone: 603-978-8279 | Email: <a href="mailto:priyankasingh30@gmail.com">priyankasingh30@gmail.com</a> | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-singh-94014719/ | GitHub: https://github.com/singhpri30 |

Portfolio: https://singhpri30.github.io/New-Portfolio/

#### **Covid-19 Tracker | Front-End Developer |**

**GitHub Repo Link:** <a href="https://github.com/Team-1-UNH-Bootcamp/Group-Project-1">https://github.com/Team-1-UNH-Bootcamp/Group-Project-1</a> **Deployed App:** <a href="https://team-1-unh-bootcamp.github.io/Group-Project-1/index.html">https://team-1-unh-bootcamp.github.io/Group-Project-1/index.html</a>

- **Description:** The COVID-19 Tracker is an application that will assist organizations across NH in administering their screenings as well as provide their staff with important resources, communications, and data surrounding COVID-19.
- Responsibilities: To create COVID-Stats page. On COVID Stats page, the user can check covid-19 statistics in World, USA, and NH. The Covid statistics are represented in different formats. The JavaScript library "Chart.js" has been used to create charts.
- Tools / Languages used: HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma CSS framework, API, Ajax, Chart.js

### Relevant Experience

# Portware India Pvt. Ltd. -Sr. Test Engineer: Oct 2012 – Apr 2014 (Clients-Carlson, Scotia Capital, RBC)

- Responsible for requirement analysis, estimation, test scenarios and requirement traceability matrix
- Experience in Smoke, Regression, Functional, Integration, GUI, and End to End Testing.
- Experience in Test Execution, Identification of Defects, Defect Logging, and reporting.
- Experience in backend testing by executing SQL queries.
- Experience in Automation of test cases using QF-Test Automation tool.

### Capgemini, India – Sr. Quality Engineer: Aug 2010 – Oct 2012 (Client-Serco UK)

- Experience in Requirement Understanding, Test Scenario Identification, Test Case creation, execution, and review.
- Experience in Defect Management using TFS (Team Foundation Server-Microsoft)
- Experience in the creation and execution of test cases for functional and non-functional requirements.
- Experience in User Acceptance Testing at Client location Derby (United Kingdom).

# Cimcon Software India Pvt. Ltd.- V&V Engineer: Jan 2009 – Aug 2010 (Clients-TD Bank and InTotality Inc)

- Experience in the creation and execution of test cases for functional and non-functional requirements.
- Experience in logging discrepancies found in the application using Mantis bug tracking tool
- Hands-on experience in Smoke Testing, Functionality Testing, Validation Testing, Regression Testing, and Stress Testing, Usability Testing.
- Experience in Face book Integration Testing.